— Michelle Blackwell • —

Systems & Platforms Coordinator

CONTACT

912-590-4746



@mblackwellGCA



mblack804@aol.com



Github

PROFILE

After working in the business sector for nine years culminating in office management, I transitioned into education in 2007 and have worked for Georgia Cyber Academy (GCA) since 2008. My journey with GCA has led to engaging in different roles from teaching, leading, piloting new programs like the Family Success Liaisons, and also wearing different hats such as tech support collaboration with K12 inc., curriculum designer with LearnZillion, lead teacher, operations assistant principal, LMS administrator, and currently, Systems & Platforms Coordinator. Georgia Cyber Academy truly allows me to practice my Bachelors in Psychology and my Masters of Teaching degrees!

PROFICIENT SKILLS

- MICROSOFT OFFICE SUITE
- GOOGLE SUITE
 - O GOOGLE CERTIFIED EDUCATOR L1
- **O**RGANIZATION
 - **PRIORITIZING**
 - **M**ULTITASKING
 - TIME MANAGEMENT
 - O PROJECT MANAGEMENT

EMFRGING SKILLS

- FS WEB DEVELOPER
 - **GIT-THERE**
 - Password-Generator
 - E-COMMERCE BACK-END

EDUCATION

Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond VA. 2006

Masters of Teaching

EXPERIENCE

Systems and Platforms Coordinator

2021 - Current

The Systems and Platforms Coordinator is responsible for all elements of managing the Learning Management System, Canvas Instructure and Infinite Campus Instruction/Tools. The SPC ensures the effective collection, analysis, maintenance, and reporting of data for students within Georgia Cyber Academy's Student Information System as well as ensures the effective collaboration and dissemination of school operations across all grade bands. The Systems and Platforms Coordinator will oversee the integration, implementation, support, and usage of school-level technology resources and platforms in conjunction with district-level personnel. Additionally, as the SPC, utilize coding skills (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, to enhance the LMS experience for students and staff.

Systems & Platforms Specialist

2019-2021

The Systems and Platforms Specialist supports all elements of the instructional operational platforms including Infinite Campus, Canvas, Jigsaw Interactive, etc. The SPS ensures the effective collection, analysis, maintenance, and accuracy of data within Georgia Cyber Academy's platforms. The Systems and Platforms Specialist will support the implementation and usage of school-level technology resources and platforms in conjunction with district-level personnel. As the SPS for K-12, primary responsibilities are to ensure Canvas Instructure, Jigsaw Interactive, and Infinite Campus (as it relates to Canvas) are developed and functioning optimally. This includes the onboarding of new staff and students via maintaining the sync between programs or entering manually as well as troubleshooting as needed. Additional primary responsibilities are to provide staff and student training resources via job aids, tutorials, training modules, training courses, consultation, and support tickets. Likewise, research new ways to achieve goals and new ways to use our programs that benefit students and staff. Additional responsibilities include attending team, grade-band, and district meetings to ensure accurate and efficient use of programs.

Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond VA.

2006

Bachelor of Psychology

North GA College & State University, Dahlonega GA.

2011

Gifted Endorsement

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Numerous Conferences

2018, 2019, 2020, 2021, 2022

- FETC
- GAETC
- ISTE
- InstructureCon
- DLAC
- GASSP

K12 Teacher Ambassador

2016-2018

A group of diverse, high-energy, and creative Teacher Ambassadors to serve as public spokespeople and advocates on issues ranging from virtual learning, the online teaching profession, academics, school-related news and updates, and education policy through blogging, media interviews, event participation, and K12 campaigns

K12 Manager Development

2016

What is the purpose of K12's Manager Development program? We believe that putting students first begins with equipping our managers with the tools and resources for greater self-knowledge and best management practices. We want to foster a culture that is action-oriented and focused on results; a culture of professionalism, continuous improvement, service, transparency, innovation, accountability, and most importantly, the highest level of integrity at every level of our organization.

Georgia Tech Full Stack Dev

2021-2022

A Full Stack Web Developer coding boot camp that covers a full stack of coding languages and frameworks: from front-end development to back-end development such as HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, React.js,

Middle School Operations Assistant Principal

2015-2019

Lead and support a team of 113 teachers, 13 lead teachers, and 4,300 6th-8th grade students. Utilize the GA TKES platform to provide feedback and support for direct reports. Collect, analyze, and disseminate data that helps articulate GCA's mission and vision to ensure all stakeholders have a common understanding and are positioned to work cooperatively to achieve desired results; utilizes/relies heavily upon communication technologies and practices that most effectively support a predominately virtual/remote environment. Manages and maintains multiple systems and projects for beginning, semester-end, and year-end semester transitions, student enrollment, scheduling placement, transcripts, progress, intervention, and support for students and staff. Work collaboratively with K12 Inc. to provide the necessary integration support for all processes including the student information system, Infinite Campus, and the learning management system, Total View School.

8th Grade Lead Teacher

2014-2015

Lead and support a team of 8 teachers and 1500 8th grade students. Utilize the GA TKES platform to provide feedback and support for direct reports. Frequently collect and analyze data on student and teacher performance from multiple systems to determine effectiveness and strategies for improvement. Plans/implements data-driven professional learning activities. Works collaboratively with others to achieve school performance goals. Serves as a liaison between parents and teachers along with the school administrative team. Presents and leads various school and department/team meetings.

Middle School Department Chair – Social Studies

2013-2014

Lead social studies teachers in grades 6-8 in meeting the mission and vision of the school. Using data to determine areas of strengths and weaknesses, lead professional development and lead professional learning communities. Supervise grade-level social studies chair-persons. Develop lesson plans and resources for the team.

8th Grade Teacher – Social Studies

2013-2014

Maintain the mission and vision of school goals. Teach the Georgia State Standards. Developing lifelong learners.

Technology Coordinator

2011-2014

Host technology workshops to assist teachers with developing their technology skills. Point of contact for Elementary school teachers' technology issues/questions. Research new ideas to implement technology in the classroom and present to staff

Grade Level Chair - 5th Grade

2009-2013

Lead teachers in meeting the mission and vision of the school. Lead professional development and lead professional learning communities. Disseminate and follow up on directives as needed.

5th Grade Teacher - Math

2008-2013

API, MySQL, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Git, and more!

Maintaining the mission and vision of school goals. Teach the Georgia State Standards. Developing lifelong learners at Georgia Cyber Academy, GA.

FUN-FACT

GCA Esports

2021

Working with a team to create GCA's first esports program; Georgia's first virtual esports team!

Canvas API Workshop

2021

Training to learn more about using API calls with Postman & Canvas Instructure.

RELATED EXPERIENCE

LearnZillion

2012-2014

Selected from over 10,000 applicants to be a member of the LearnZillion Dream Team creating instructional content in math.

5th Grade Teacher - Math

2007-2008

Maintain the mission and vision of school goals. Teach the Georgia State Standards. Developing lifelong learners at Ware County School, Ware County, GA.

Additional Training

Canvas Instructure Leadership Institute

2021

We bring school and district leaders together from all over the world to discuss and share insights about how to improve communication, consistency, culture, and collective teacher efficacy. Attend two 3-hour interactive, virtual sessions to collaborate and learn alongside other dynamic leaders.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Price Management

1998-2007

Performed many duties as office manager, including Accounts balancing/reconciliations, accounts payable, accounts receivable, staffing, merchandising, payroll, human resources, and inventory.